♪ A chill beat brings me back to our roots ♪
♪ Một cái beat thật chill đưa ta về với bản chất ♪
♪ Den Vau keeps it real, rap in the simplest ways ♪
♪ Đen Vâu keep it real, rap theo kiểu đơn giản nhất ♪
♪ The game has gone far. further than everything I’ve ever dreamed of ♪
♪ Cuộc chơi đi hơi xa, hơn cả thứ mà ta từng mơ về ♪
♪ Turn on a beat and watch Den Vau write poetry ♪
♪ Bật cho ta con beat, coi Đen Vâu tiếp tục làm thơ nà ♪
♪ A bear can only hibernate when it has foraged enough food ♪
♪ Con gấu kiếm ăn đủ, thì nó mới có thể ngủ đông ♪
♪ Eagles learn to flap their wings before their feathers are fully-grown ♪
♪ Đại bàng tập đập cánh, trước cả khi nó đã đủ lông ♪
♪ Wolves will only become the alpha when they have endured the most wounds ♪
♪ Chịu nhiều vết thương nhất, mới đủ sức làm con sói đầu đàn ♪
♪ Especially in the face of adversity. humans must never surrender ♪
♪ Con người trong nghịch cảnh, càng không được phép chịu đầu hàng ♪
♪ Gold in the head. fire in the heart. rocks and pebbles beneath the feet ♪
♪ Trong đầu là vàng, lửa trong tim, dưới chân sỏi đá ♪
♪ No roses will grow if you do nothing but destroy ♪
♪ Không có hoa hồng, nếu không làm, mà chỉ giỏi phá ♪
♪ Perhaps the reason why I do things is simply because they’re trendy ♪
♪ Có lẽ việc ta làm, chỉ là thứ gì đó đang hợp thời ♪
♪ In an endless cluster of flowers, I’d still be satisfied as a leaf ♪
♪ Cũng vui vì làm chiếc lá, trong vô vàn hoa lá bay rợp trời ♪
♪ Blessed to not be an idol and spare a weight off my shoulders ♪
♪ Cũng may không làm idol, không phải mang gánh nặng đến trĩu vai ♪
♪ A messy song, the memory when it first hit one million likes ♪
♪ Một bài nhạc lộn xộn, kỉ niệm ngày có được một triệu like ♪
♪ If everyone gave me 1K. I would immediately become a billionaire ♪
♪ Nếu mỗi người cho ta một ngàn, là ta sẽ có ngay một tỷ đồng ♪
♪ Take the money to the countryside and build some preschool classes ♪
♪ Lấy tiền đó lên vùng xa, xây được mấy cái lớp học vỡ lòng ♪
♪ As the last rays of sunlight slowly fade away ♪
♪ Ánh nắng cuối cùng dần buông xuống ♪
♪ I suddenly crave a cup of bitter tea ♪
♪ Bỗng thấy thèm một ly trà đắng chát ♪
♪ Between the avenue of trees. someone returns to the streets ♪
♪ Ai về trên phố hai bên hàng cây ♪
♪ Tomorrow may be another day of sun ♪
♪ Mai có lẽ là một ngày nắng khác ♪
♪ A bouquet of roses easily get crushed in our palms ♪
♪ Hồng tàn một đoá nắm trong bàn tay ♪
♪ Before it follows the gust of wind and shrivels away ♪
♪ Trước khi theo con gió mà khô đi ♪
♪ For me to keep my dreams at the end of the day ♪
♪ Cho ta giữ trọn giấc mơ cuối ngày ♪
♪ So we know that we are not without feelings ♪
♪ để ta biết mình không hề vô tri ♪
♪ Call me Dunno and my friend is Doono ♪
♪ Gọi ta là Mít-đặc. bạn ta là Biết-tuốt ♪
♪ We’re on an adventure. traveling spontaneously without a plan ♪
♪ Và ta đang phiêu lưu, chuyến đi không biết trước ♪
♪ No one could anticipate. these guys that loved to sing ♪
♪ Đâu có ai mà biết được, mấy thằng thích hát ca ♪
♪ Who went from wandering around aimlessly to becoming famous rap stars ♪
♪ Lông bông từ ngày đó, đến bây giờ là rap star ? ♪
♪ The group of people in the cage are calling us eccentric ♪
♪ Đám người ở trong chuồng, nói tụi ta ngông cuồng ♪
♪ They may say I'm uncultured, but I do not feel dejected ♪
♪ Nói ta vô văn hoá, nhưng mà ta không buồn ♪
♪ More beautiful than flowers in a garden, sometimes like a doctor ♪
♪ Đẹp hơn hoa trong vườn, đôi khi như bác sĩ ♪
♪ Uncovering bottled-up thoughts deep inside, no matter what other people think ♪
♪ Moi móc hết tâm can mặc kệ người khác nghĩ ♪
♪ Already familiar with bitterness and resentment ♪
♪ Cũng đã quen với đắng cay ♪
♪ Coming in empty-handed and. at worst, leaving with my hands empty ♪
♪ Bước vào đời tay trắng cùng lắm lại trở về với trắng tay ♪
♪ When I wake up every morning, I spend some time looking at the clouds drifting by ♪
♪ Mỗi ngày ta thức dậy, dành 1 lúc ngắm nhìn mây trắng bay ♪
♪ When you love life. it will love you back passionately ♪
♪ Khi mày yêu cuộc đời, cuộc đời cũng sẽ yêu mày đắm say ♪
♪ There are too many things I have to worry about ♪
♪ Có quá nhiều thứ muốn anh chi ♪
♪ Many people hope that I will reach my downfall quickly ♪
♪ Nhiều người thì cũng muốn anh sẽ xuống nhanh đi ♪
♪ When I am still young and ripe, like a vegetable garden ♪
♪ Khi tóc còn như vườn cải, còn đang bổ luống xanh rì ♪
♪ Like Trịnh Công Sơn, I hope the wind will carry me away ♪
♪ Như Trịnh Công Sơn anh muốn để gió cuốn anh đi ♪
♪ Happiness is when you return home, seeing your mother wait for your father with the door wide open ♪
♪ Hạnh phúc là khi về nhà, mẹ vẫn chờ ba dang rộng cửa ♪
♪ In moments like these. nothing else matters anymore ♪
♪ Những lúc như thế, đời chẳng còn gì quan trọng nữa ♪
♪ You will never know how lucky you have been ♪
♪ Mày sẽ không biết mày đã từng may mắn tới cỡ nào ♪
♪ Until you have experienced the lightness of a sigh of relief ♪
♪ Cho tới khi mày hiểu được sự nhẹ nhõm của một cái thở phào ♪
♪ Please. I just want to be alone… ♪
♪ Ta chỉ muốn được yên. đừng nỡ nào... ♪
♪ As the last rays of sunlight slowly fade away ♪
♪ Ánh nắng cuối cùng dần buông xuống ♪
♪ I suddenly crave a cup of bitter tea ♪
♪ Bỗng thấy thèm một ly trà đắng chát ♪
♪ Between the avenue of trees.someone returns to the streets ♪
♪ Ai về trên phố hai bên hàng cây ♪
♪ Tomorrow may be another day of sun ♪
♪ Mai có lẽ là một ngày nắng khác ♪
♪ A bouquet of roses easily get crushed in our palms ♪
♪ Hồng tàn một đoá nắm trong bàn tay ♪
♪ Before it follows the gust of wind and shrivels away ♪
♪ Trước khi theo con gió mà khô đi ♪
♪ For me to keep my dreams at the end of the day ♪
♪ Cho ta giữ trọn giấc mơ cuối ngày ♪
♪ So we know that we are not without feelings ♪
♪ Để ta biết mình không hề vô tri ♪
♪ Be gentle but not harmless, or else they'll harass you ♪
♪ Sống phải hiền chứ đừng quá lành, lành quá tụi nó bắt nạt ♪
♪ They will strip away all you own, even your last pennies and dimes ♪
♪ Tụi nó sẽ vắt kiệt mày đến từng đồng xu cắc bạc ♪
♪ No matter who you are, they will still try to take control like an animal ♪
♪ Dù mày cầm tinh con gì, tụi nó cũng muốn cưỡi lên ♪
♪ From your head to your neck, amidst the moans and cries for help ♪
♪ Cưỡi lên đầu cưỡi lên cổ, cho dù mày có lè lưỡi rên ♪
♪ When you were once poor and destitute, your hands were dry and blistered ♪
♪ Khi mày đã từng nghèo khó, tay mày đã từng chai và sạn ♪
♪ I believe that one day, you will know the friends who remain by your side ♪
♪ Tao tin là mày sẽ biết, bên mày có ai là bạn ♪
♪ Try falling for once and see, not many people will help you get up ♪
♪ Thử ngã một lần mà coi, mấy ai chịu đỡ mày đâu ♪
♪ Most will laugh in your face and push you deeper into the ground ♪
♪ Đa số là cười vào mặt, rồi tiện thể đạp xuống thật sâu ♪
♪ Because life’s a game, as sour as a pickle ♪
♪ Vì trò đời mà, chua như là dưa ghém ♪
♪ People like bringing others down to hide their own feelings of insecurity ♪
♪ Tụi nó thích hạ thấp người khác để che đậy cảm giác thua kém ♪
♪ They’ll criticize you with an intellect similar to that of a Kindergartener's ♪
♪ Tụi nó sẽ phán xét mày bằng tư duy chưa quá lớp chồi ♪
♪ When you fall. they laugh loudly, like a fish biting its prey ♪
♪ Mày ngã. tụi nó cười to, mồm nó há như cá đớp mồi ♪
♪ They aren't difficult to find, just throw a little bit of fodder ♪
♪ Rải một chút cám cò, tìm tụi nó không cần phải lội ao ♪
♪ I sometimes regret it. the affection that I gave away too quickly ♪
♪ Nhiều khi tao thấy tiếc, niềm thân ái mà tao đã vội trao ♪
♪ They won't appear when they do not see any opportunities for benefit ♪
♪ Tụi nó sẽ không xuất hiện khi không thấy được một chút lợi nào ♪
♪ You can be my friend, but don’t try to become the boss of me ♪
♪ Làm bạn tao thì được, đừng có muốn làm ông cố nội tao! ♪
♪ As the last rays of sunlight slowly fade away ♪
♪ Ánh nắng cuối cùng dần buông xuống ♪
♪ I suddenly crave a cup of bitter tea ♪
♪ Bỗng thấy thèm một ly trà đắng chát ♪
♪ Between the avenue of trees, someone returns to the streets ♪
♪ Ai về trên phố hai bên hàng cây ♪
♪ Tomorrow may be another day of sun ♪
♪ Mai có lẽ là một ngày nắng khác ♪
♪ A bouquet of roses easily get crushed in our palms ♪
♪ Hồng tàn một đoá nắm trong bàn tay ♪
♪ Before it follows the gust of wind and shrivels away ♪
♪ Trước khi theo con gió mà khô đi ♪
♪ For me to keep my dreams at the end of the day ♪
♪ Cho ta giữ trọn giấc mơ cuối ngày ♪
♪ So we know that we are not without feelings ♪
♪ Để ta biết mình không hề vô tri ♪